in this video I'm going to just
demonstrate some of the other formatting
and structural tools that you can use to
create your presentation as you can see
for this presentation I created this
from a new blank presentation which
primarily gives me full control over the
layout and design of each of the slides
I'll start with the white background and
then I then have to decide what the
layout of the slide will be how it will
be structured what text will be used
what font what size how it will be
colored and I have full control over
that alternatively you can select a
pre-formatted template so if I want to
fail and I've got the option for a blank
presentation or then I can select more
themes and then that gives me a wide
range of templates and themes that I can
select from I could pick any one of
those and then straight away I've got a
formatting option
everything's been applied I would then
just need to populate the actual
presentation so if I click on that one
there and select create one of the
issues here is the file size it's very
big and that will be because of the the
quality of the images and the resolution
of the images so if you're constrained
by file size you may find that you need
to be careful on the type of
presentation on the type of template
that you're using so as you can see this
has already been formatted in a certain
way and if I click on new slate and I
select the title slide to content slate
as you can see there are various form on
the elements that have already been
applied so if I just actually close that
one down go back to the original
presentation as I see I have full
control over this one so if I was
following a house tale this would be
more probably because then I could apply
the various formatting in the same that
needs to be applied following the
company guidelines when we're
with your presentation you still have
the option to apply a variety of themes
or design styles to that if I go to the
design tab as you can see I have a range
of themes along the top so if I just
move my cursor along each theme so
that's the theme I'm using at the moment
which is office theme which is a default
theme I can then move it further along
and have fuss at the gallery theme
integral theme and as you can see it
makes changes so it's giving you an
example of what your presentation will
look like if you select our theme again
there are a wide range of themes that
you may wish to use so at the moment I'm
just sticking with the one that was the
original one you also have variants of
the themes so the colors can be changed
all the different as you can see it when
I move my cursor down through these it's
changing the various effects so I can
select a variety of different features
and different tools to apply to the
slate you also have the design idea so
very similar the templates if I click on
the design ideas it looks at the
presentation and then it generates ideas
based around up so as you can see it is
looking at various ways of structuring
the information so if I'd to say that
that I wanted to go with one of those
all I would do would be to click on that
and then that would change the layout
and structure of the slate to fit and
I'll just close that down and undo that
so that's covering the themes designs
and styles as I see some of the most
popular ones are quite straightforward
and that will apply that to every slate
within the presentation as you can see
you would then need to go back in
because the the text there isn't working
it should be black text again so I would
have to go back in and change that
unchain to the the color of the text
again the chart is going over the border
into there so as you can see there are
elements that you would still
to go in and change but if you were
happy with an actual design theme you
would then just be able to work with
that and make the changes that you need
it to so I'm just going to undo adding
that so I'm back to my plan for slide
presentation that I've applied me when
formatting to it maybe a kiss that all I
need to do is I'm happy with having just
plain white slate book and maybe add a
slightly different background color so
again if I can just go to the design tab
I can look at the format background so
if I click on that it will allow me to
select a range of options so I have a
solid fill then I can pick a color and
so I could go for
perhaps that color that will
automatically apply that but it only
applies that to that slate I'd need to
select apply to all to make sure that it
would select that and apply it to all
the slate so if I do that now as you can
see each of the slate now has that color
apply to it I'm just going to undo that
and undo that so again I can look
through all the colors is there anything
else more appropriate I could also have
what's called a gradient fill which
applies some form of shared ingredient
to the color so it goes from white down
to blue and you can play around with the
preset gradients in of Lynnea
rectangular so a variety of tools that
you can mess about with have a look see
what you like again do I apply that to
all slate
does that look good I'm quite happy with
that yep that's great and I can also
have a picture or texture infill so I
could have a picture applied now I have
a picture set up as defaults or it's
actually applied that as the background
there so I just don't do that
and go back to the gradient fill so I'm
quite happy with that or a pattern fill
again you would select the pattern that
you wish and what I'm quite happy with
the creating fill because I think with
it being the presentation about balloon
raids
the blue and the sky looks okay so once
you're happy with the the background of
the presentation close that down and
again it's more about just adding some
structure and definition to each of the
individual slides so I'll go back to the
Home tab again I'm going to go and
select a black border for that and black
border for that and the infill I will
use again I'm just going to stick with
the one that I selected originally and
again for this one border around that
border around uh do the infill and at
the moment I'm quite happy with the
layout and the design that I've applied
to that